energymatters.com.au 2008-12-18

# Privacy Policy : Solar Power & Wind Energy : solar panels, wind generators, batteries, inverters - Energy Matters

## 1\. Overview 

Please read our privacy policy carefully. As part of the normal operation of our services we collect, use and from time to time, disclose information about you to third parties. This Privacy Policy governs the information we collect about you and your use of information we provide to you. 

By accepting this Privacy Policy and the User Guidelines, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in the manner prescribed in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the Energy Matters' User Agreement. 

The privacy practices of this notice apply to the Energy Matters website (collectively the " **Site** "). Energy Matters operates under similar privacy practices as described in this Privacy Policy and, subject to the requirements of applicable law and, in the case of Australia, the requirements of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), (as amended by the private sector provisions which came into effect on 21 December 2001) (the " **Privacy Act** ") and in the case of New Zealand, the requirements of the Privacy Act of 1993. 

## 2\. Information we collect

  * This information is collected in order to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customize our services to make your experience safer and easier. 

  * We may require some additional necessary financial information, such as, but not limited to: if you are registering using an email account at a free email service. We use your financial information, including credit card information to verify your name, address, and other contact information, as well as to bill you for your use of our services. 

  * We collect data about you to do internal research. The information may include the URL you came from, your IP address, your browser, cookie information. 

  * If you choose to buy on our Site, we collect information about your use of our site. 

## 3\. Use of the information

We use the information to target and customise our advertising, to advise of products and services including new products. 

## 4\. Disclosure of your information

We cannot and do not guarantee, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. 

  * E.g. we may be forced to disclose information to the government or pursuant to legal requests

## 5\. Security

Perfect security does not exist on the internet. However, we use industry standards to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information. 

## 6\. Changes

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time based on your comments and our need to accurately reflect our data collection and disclosure practices. All changes to this policy are effective after we provide you with at least thirty (30) day's notice of the changes by posting the changes on the Energy Matters announcements board or by email notification. We provide you with thirty (30) days notice to allow you the opportunity to notify Energy Matters if you do not agree to such changes. 

## 7\. Children

No person under 18 is allowed to use this service unsupervised (i.e. without your parents or guardians). Additionally, if you are under the age of 18, do not submit any personal information to us.
